Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Leon Kolb, collector. Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints
ca. 1600-1800
M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
9.0 Linear feet
The subjects include rulers, statesmen, authors, scholars and other famous personages from ancient times to the nineteenth century. Most of the prints were produced in the 17th and 18th centuries from paintings by Has Holbein, Anthony Vandyke, Godfrey Kneller, Peter Lely and other noted artists.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Arranged by name of subject, each print in Series 1 is numbered for convenient reference in the various indices in the printed catalogue by Susan Lenkey. Painters and engravers, printing techniques and social and historical positions of the subjects are identified and indexed as well.The subjects include rulers, statesmen, authors, scholars and other famous personages from ancient times to the nineteenth century. Most of the prints were produced in the 17th and 18th centuries from paintings by Has Holbein, Anthony Vandyke, Godfrey Kneller, Peter Lely and other noted artists. Dr. Kolb, Clinical Associate Professor Emeritus of Pharmacology in the Stanford School of Medicine, was a collector of books, pictures, and objects d'art.
Materials in Series 2 are not referenced in the printed catalogue by Lenkey, and are described to the folder-level.
Access to Collection
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. and Mrs. Leon Kolb, 1972. Accessions 1972-002 and 2010-110.
Biographical/Historical Note
Dr. Kolb, Clinical Associate Professor Emeritus of Pharmacology in the Stanford School of Medicine, was a collector of books, prints, and objects d'art.
Container List
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 0001. Abbott Charles 1st baron Tenderden, 1762-1832 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Charles Abbott Baron Tenterden, Lord Chief Justice of the Kings Bench, Tenderden. Painted by J.W.Wright. Engraved by W.Holl. Fisher Son & Co London 1836. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 22.4 x 14.7 cm.
  - 0002. Abbott George abp. of Canterbury, 1562-1633 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Abbot Arch Bishop of Canterbury. From an original picture in the possession of Mr. Kingsley. Jacobus Houb raken s culp. Amst. Bust looking slightly left in lettered oval in symbolic Baroque surounding. From: Birch T. The Heads of the Most illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J. Knapton London 1756. Engraving. 36.2 x 22.8 cm. Singer No. 9/18.
  - 0003. Abbott, George, Archbishop of Canterbury, 1562-1633 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    George Abbot Archbishop of Canterbury. From the original in the Collection of The Right Honble The Earl of Verulam. Drawn by R.W.Satchwell; Engraved with Permission by C.Picart. London.Published March 25 by Lackington. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 37.2 x 26.4 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0004. Aberdeen, George Hamilton Gordon, 4th earl of, 1784-1800
    Item missing. Statesman, English. George, Earl of Aberdeen,/K.T. F.R.S. F.S.A./Painted by Tho. Lawrence Esq. R.A. Principal Painter in Ordinary to his Majesty./Engraved by G. Turner. London Pub.d Oct. 25th. 1900 by C. Turner, 50 Warren St. Fitzroy Sqe. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 36.5 x 26.8 cm.
  - 0005. Adaini Adam bp. of Hildesheim, 1603-1663 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Adamus Adami Prior in Murhart; Ord. S. Bened. S.Theol. D.Electus Abbas Huisburgensis III.mi Principis/Corbeiensis et Praelatorum Imperialium nec non Abbatissarun Principum et Imperialium ad Tractatus Pacis Universalis cum Plenipotentia Legatus. Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Corn. Galle sculpsit. accipit Privilegium Caesareum. Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae ordinum. 1649. Bust looking right in oval lettered: ''Angeli Pacis amare elebunt." Engraving. - 30.5 x 19.3 cm. Singer No. 96/234. No. 124. from: Pacificatores orbis Christianun. Rotterdam 1697.
  - 0006. Addison Joseph, 1672-1719 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Joseph Addison Esq. In the Collection of Jacob Jonson Esq. G.Kneller pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Ama. 1748. From: Birch T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly right surrounded by symbolic Baroque elements. Engraving. 36.0 x 22.8 cm. Singer No. 104/263.
  - 0007. Adelaide [Sachsen-Koburg-Meiningen], Queen of [William IV.]. Ruler, English. W., 1792-1899 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Bust in oblong looking slightly right. Mezzotint. 52 x 35.6 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0008. Adolph Friedrich von Holstein Gottorp, 1710-1771 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Adolph Friedrich/erwehiter Schwedischer/Thron-Folger,/Sysang Sc. Lips. Knee-piece in oblong looking slightly right. Engraving. 29.8 x 18.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 150/366.
  - 0009. Agnolo, Andrea [del Sarto], 1488-1530 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Andrea del Sarto./Andrea del Sarto dip. V.Gozzini disegno. G.Saunders inc. Firenze 1824./Dall originale esistente nella Galleria della mobil Famiglia Ricci. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 30.0 x 21.0 cm.
  - 0010. Aguesseau, Henri François, 1668-1751 (Flat-box 1, Folder 1)
    Le Chancelier/d'Aguesseau./R.Tourniere Pinxit. 1720. P. Maloeuvre Sculp. 1772. Bust in oval looking left in oblong. Engraving. 25.4 x 18.5 cm. Singer No. 217/514.
  - 0011. Akenside, Mark, 1721-1770
    Item missing. Poet and physician, English. Mark Akenside (signed)./Author of/the Pleasures of Imagination./Pond. Richard Woodman./ Fisher Son & Co. London, 1838. Right profile in oblong. Mezzotint. 11.7 x 9.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed of f.
    Item missing.
  - 0012. Albia Terentia, mother of Otho, 8th emperor of Rome., 1st century A.D. (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    W.Albia Terentia Othonis Mater./[Double quatrain under portrait.]Aegidius Sadeler S.C.M. sculp. Marcus Sadeler excudit. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. No.IIX. Engraving. 35.2 x 24.4 cm.
  - 0013. Alba, Fernando Alvarez de Toledo, duque de, 1508-1582 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    Ferdinand Alvarez Herzog von Alba geb. 15O8; gest. zu Lissabon 1582. Entsprossen aus einem mit K~nigen verwandten Geschlechte ruhmgekrnter Feldherr Karls des V. in den ZUgen in Italien, Afrika Ungarn und Deutschland, Statthalter Philipps II. in den Niederlanden:von 1567 bis l573;als Greisnoch im Jahre 1580 Eroberer von Portugal fur seinen Konig Philipp 11. Das Original ist in der K.K.Ambraser Samlung. zu Wie. Bust in oval looking left. Stipple-engraving. 24.6 x 14.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0014. Alba, Fernando Alvarez de Toledo, duque de, 1508-1582 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    Ferdinand of Toledo Duke of Alva/Governour of the Low Countreys./Ro. Vaughan Sculp. L.6. fol. 25. Bust in oval looking slightly right. Engraving. 16.1 x 10.7 Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0015. Albemarle, George Monk, 1st duke of, 1608-1670 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    George Monk, Duke of Albemarle./From the original of Sir Peter Lely,in/The Town Hall, Exeter./Drawn by H.Crease; Engraved [with Permission] by W.J.Fry/London Published Feb. 1.1816, by Lackington, Allen and Co. and Longman Hurst Rees, Orme and Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 0016. Albert, prince consort of Queen Victoria, 1819-1861 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    His Royal Highness The Prince Albert 1844./Painted by H. Thorburn./drawn on stone by Fr.Hanfstaengl. /printed in the lithographical institution of Fr.Hanfstaengl at Munich. Knee-piece oblong looking left. 37.8 x 27.0 cm. Lithograph.
  - 0017. Albert [Albrecht], duke of Saxony, 1443-1500 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    Albertus Saxoniae Dux. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 28.8 x 16.4 cm.
  - 0018. Albrecht, Wilhelm Eduard, 1800-1876 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    W.E. Albrecht, Gem. v. Schultz. lith. v. Krafft. Kon. lith. Institut zu Berlin. Verlag v. Gebruder Rocca in Berlin und Gottingen. Lithograph. 20.7 x17.4 cm.
  - 0019. Alessandro Farnese, duke of Parma and Piacenza, 1545-1592 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    Alexander Farnese, Due de Parme./Adrian van der Werf ft pinx. P. de Gunst sculps./ Bust in oval frame looking left. Quatrain under picture: "La France par trois fois me céda la victoire,/Et j’eusse triomphé du Belgique Lion,/Si le jaloux Philippe avoit voulu me croire,/Plut6t que ses soupçons et son ambition.” Engraving. 32.0 x 18.1 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 421/1320.
  - 0020. Alessandro Farnese, duke of Parma and Piacenza, 1545-1592 (Flat-box 1, Folder 2)
    Copy 2.
  - 0021. Alessandro Farnese, duke of Parma and Piacenza, 1545-1592 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Governor of the Netherlands. Military officer, Italian. Alexander Farnese. Hartogh van Patina, en Plaisance. Gouverneur Generaelen. Veldtoverste In de Spaenche Nederlanden. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 26.6 x 18.1 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0022. Alexander [the Great], 365-323 B.C. (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Alexander the Great. Published as the Act directs March 19, 1796. Right profile in oval. Stipple-engraving. 15.9 x 11.4 cm.
  - 0023. Alexander VII,[Fabio Chigi], pope, 1599-1667 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Alexander VII. Pont. Opt. Max. Justitia et Veritate. [Quatrain in cartouche]. Corn, Vischer delin. sculp. Clemendt de Jonghe excudit. Bust in lettered oval looking left. Engraving. 31.0 x 24.0 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0024. Alexander VIII., [Pietro Ottoboni], 1610-1691 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Alexander VIII. Ottobonus Venet: Pontifex Maximus. Ex Formis Nicolai Vischer. Cum Privilego: Praepotentiss D.D. Ordinum General: Belgij foederati. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 36.7 x 27.5 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0025. Alexandra, queen Consort of Edward VII, 1844-1925 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Alexandra. Engraved by William Holl from photography by Mayall Osborne March 14 1863. Published March 24.1863 by John Mitchell Bookseller & Publisher to Her Majesty and Their Royal Highnesses, The Prince and Princess of Wales, 33, Old Bond Street, London. Printed by Mc Queen. Knee-piece in oval looking left. Stipple-engraving. 43.7 x 33.4 cm.
  - 0026. Alfred I, [the Great] King of England, 849-901 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Engraving. 28.7 x 18.8 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0027. Amalia von Solms Prinzessin von Nassau-Orange, 1602-? (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Emeliae De Solns, D.G. Princeps Arausionensium, Comitissa Nassaviae Etc. Antonius van Dyck pinxit. Conraet Waumans sculpsit. excudit. From: Iconography of Vandyke. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Engraving. 25.3 x 13.3 cm. Singer No. 610/1992. Dutuit No. 153.2.e. Mauquoy,H. No: 152.11. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0028. Amalie Elisabeth v.d. Pfalz widowed landgravess of Hessen-Kassel, 1549-1609 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Aemilie Elizabeth D.G. Lantgrave de Hesse,/Comtesse De Hannaw et Muntzenb:/ B.Moncornet ex. cum privilegio. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 16.6 x 12.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0029. Amalie Elisabeth, landgravess of Hessen-Kassel, 1602-1651 (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Amelia Elisabetha, Dei gratia Hassiae Landgravia. Nata Comitissa Hanoviae Muntzenbergensis, Comitissa Cattimeliboci, Deciae Ziegenhaynae, et Niddae, Inferioris Hassiae, tutorio Nomine, P.T. Regens, Anselmus van Hulle pinxit. Petrus de lode sculpsit. Accessit privilegium Caesareum Cum privilegio Regum et Hollandiae ordinuni etc. 1651. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Pur et loyal." - Engraving. 35.1 x 25.4 cm. Singer No. 609/1985. Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 23 from an undentified edition of Hulle, A. van. Celeberrimi ad pacificandum Christiani nominis orbem legati.
  - 0030. Andrada, Leitao, Francisco d', 17th century (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
    Franciscus de Andrada Leitao. Regis Portugaliae Sacri Consistorij Consiliarus Senator Aulicus, Equestris Ordinis D.N. Jesu Christi Miles Cruci ferus ad Regem Angliae nec non unitos foederati Belgij Ord.nes Generales Legatum nuper Extraordinarius, nunc ad Generales Pacis Tractatus itidem Plenipotentiarius Extraordinarius etc. Bust looking right in oval lettered: "Melior est tuta pax quam sperata victoria." Engraving. 31.6 x 20.5 cm. No. 58 from Hulle, A. van. Pacificatores orbis Christiani.Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 0031. Ann Boleyn, queen of England, 1507-1536 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Ann Bullen Queen of K. Henry VIII. J.Houbraken sculps. Amst. Holben pinx. In the Collection of the late Earl of Bradford. Impensis J. & P.Knapton Londini, 1738. From: Birch, T. The Heads of the most Illustrious Persons in Great Britain. J.Knapton, London, 1743. Bust looking left in lettered oval, surrounded by baroque symbols: angel with torch, axe and rolling head; mourner with angel and skull. Engraving. 36.8 x 25.5 cm. Singer No. 791/2522.
  - 0032. Ann Boleyn, queen of England, 1507-1536 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Ruler, English, W. Anne Boleyn. Grignion sculp.
  - 0033. Ann of Cleves, queen of England, 1515-1561 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Ann of Cleves, Queen of K.Henry VIII./in the collection of Thomas Barrett Esqr./ Holben pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Amst. 1739./Impensis J. and P.Knapton Londini, 1740. Bust facing viewer in florid baroque oval. Cupid with crown at lower left. Engraving. 37.3 x 23.5 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 792/2536.
  - 0034. Anna, queen of France, 1601-1666 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Anne Daustriche P.L.G. de Dieu Reine de France et de Navarre./Mignard pinxit.. Nanteuil Sculpebat. 1660. Bust in lettered oval looking right. Engraving. 32.7 x 24.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off. Singer No. 800/2624.
  - 0035. Anne of Denmark, queen of James I. of England., 1574-1619 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Anne of Denmark./Queen of K.James 1./Jacobus Houbraken sculpsit Amst. C.Johnson pinx. At Somerset House. From: Birch, T. The Heads of the most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J.Knaptou, London, 1743. Bust in lettered oval looking left surrounded by symbolic composition. Engraving. 36.7 x 25.1 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0036. Anne Queen of James I. of England, VI of Scotland, 1574-1619 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Queen Anne at Kensington Palace G.Kneller pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Amst. 1744. From: Birch, T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J.Knapton, London, 1756. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly right surrounded by symbolic baroque composition. Engraving. 35.5 x 22.9 cm.
  - 0037. Antin, Louis Antoine de Pardaillan de Gondrin, duke of Hofmann, 1665-1736 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    D.D.Pet. De Pardaillan de Gondrin D'Antin, Episc. Lingonsis. Dux and Par. Fran. Van Loo pinxit. Drevet scul. Bust facing viewer in lettered oval, with: "Offerebant sacerdotes Oratorii Seminari: Engraving. 24.9 x 17.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0038. Antoninus, Marcus Annius Verro [Marcus Aurelius]. 17th Emperor of Rome, 121-180 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    The Emperor Marcus Aurelius./P.Dujardin engr./Gebbie & Co./The Illustrated History of Rome. Unframed bust facing viewer Photo-engraving. 36.5 x 26.6 cm.
  - 0039. Antoninus, Marcus Annius Verro [Marcus Aurelius]. 17th Emperor of Rome, 121-180 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    M.Aurelius Imp. Horatius Pacificus formis. Right profile in oblong. Engraving. 19.0 x 15.3 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0040. Antoninus Pius, Titus Aurelius, 16th Emperor of Rome, 86-161 (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
    Antoninus Pius Imp. Left profile in oblong. Engraving. 18.8 x 15.4 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0041. Antoninus Pius, Titus Aurelius, 86-161 A.D. 16th Emperor of Rome (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    The Emperor Antoninus Pius. P.Dujardin eng. Gebbie and Co. Unframed bust facing viewer. Photo-engraving. 36.5 x 26.7 cm. Torn from book
  - 0042. Arc, Jeanne d', 1412-1431 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Das Franckreich von den Englischen errettende Fraulein Jane von Orleans,II, Theil p. 526. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 16.0 x 9.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0043. Arenberg, Albert duke of Barbancon, 1600-1670 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Albertus, Princeps. Con. Aremberg. Princ. Barbanson. Com. Aigremontan, et Rup. in Ardenn, Vicecom. Davens. Par Hannon. et Civit Leod. et Nonti. in Hannon. Advocat. Perpet. Aur. Vell. Eq'Etc, S.A.Bolswert sculp. Ant van Dyck pinxit. Cum privilegio. From: Iconography of Vandyke. Half-portrait in oblong looking right Engraving. 24.6 x 18.2 cm. Singer No. 965/3150. Dutuit No. 25.5e. Mauquoy H. No: 19.VI.
  - 0044. Aretino, Pietro, 1492-1556 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Pierre Aretin, natif d’Arezzo en Toscane, mort ~ Venise en 1556, gé de 66 ans. Bearded bust, facing viewer in oval. Verse in lower center: "Toi, dont la plume tdméraire/Censura les Rois de la Terre,/Qui fun auteur d’écrits licencieux,/Et mis au jour tant de livre pieux,/Tu dois tre pour ton salaire,/Moitid dana lea enfers, et inoitid dams les cieux.”/Mr.Moraine. Engraving. 14.7 x 10.0 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0045. Argenson,Marc Pierre de Voyer de Paulmy, 1696-1764 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Le Conte d'Argenson. Nattier pinx. Le Vasseur scuips. Bust in oval looking right in oblong. Engraving. 26.1 x 18.4 cm.
  - 0046. Argyll, John Campbell, duke of Greenwich, 2nd duke of, 1678-1743 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Col.1 John Campbell afterwards Duke of Argyll. Heath Sculpt. Bust in oval looking left. Stipple-engraving. 18.7 x 14.4 cm.
  - 0047. Argyll, John Campbell, duke of Greenwich, 2nd duke of, 1678-1743 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    John Duke of Argyll and Greenwich. In the Collection of Sr.Anthony Wescomb Bart. Aikman pinxit. J. Houbraken Sculp. Amsterdam. Bust in lettered oval looking left in Baroque composition. Engraving. 35.9 x 22.8 cm.
  - 0048. Aristoteles, 384-322 B.C. (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Aristoteles. Rembrandt Inventor. F.L.D. Ciartres excudit. Facing bust in oblong. Etching. 21.7 x 18.2 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 35 from unidentified series.
  - 0049. Arlington, Henry Bennett, earl of, 1618-1685 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Henry Bennett, Earl of Arlington in the Collection of Sr. Thomas Hanmer Bart. P.Lely pinx. J.Houbraken scuips. Ainsterdam./Inpensis J. & P.Knapton Londini, 1739. From: Birch, T. The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain. J.Knapton. London 1743. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly right surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 37.1 x 23.4 cm.
  - 0050. Arnauld d'Andilly, Antoine, 1612-1694 (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
    Arnauld D'Andilli. Jac.Lubin Sculp. Bust in oval looking slightly left. Engraving. 25.0 x 19.3 cm.
  - 0051. Arnauld, d'Andilly Antoine, 1612-1694 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Antoine Arnauld Docteur de Sorbonne. Champagne pinx. Lud.Simonneau sculp. Bust in oval facing viewer. Engraving 25.8 x 19.7 cm. Singer No. 1033/3360.
  - 0052. Arnauld, Marié Angelique, 1591-1661 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    La mere Marie Angelique Arnauld, derniare Abbesse titulaire de Port Royal Ordre de Cisteaux qui n'estant agee que de dix sept ans fut la premiere de cet Ordre en France qui renouvella dams son Abbaye l'estroite observance & l'ancien esprit de S.Bernard. Son humllitae luy ayant tous jours donne im extreme desir de quitter sa charge elle l'executa en 163O ayant obtenu permission du Roy de la rendre elective & triannale. Elle est morte le 6.Aoust 1661 agee de 70 ama. Tous ceux/qui l'ont connue ont admire entre ses autres vertus cette charitae si ardante et si desinteresse qui l'a rendue Mere de tant de fllles sans y considerer que les richesses de la grace et ne luy a jamais permis d'en refuser aucune pour le manquemt des biens temporels. Ph.Champaigne pingebat. P.van Schuppen sculpeb. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 31.8 x 24.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 0053. Arundell, Lady Blanche, Defender of Wardour Castle, 1583-1649 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Blanch Somerset, Baroness Arundell of Wardour./From the Collection of/The Right Hon.ble Lord Arundell of Wardour./Drawn by W.Hilton,R.A. Engraved (with permission)by E.Scriven./London. Published Dec. 25,1820 by Lackington, Hughes, Harding, Mayor and Jones, and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme and Brown. Knee-piece looking right. Stipple-engraving. 37.7 x 25.7 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 0054. Arundel and Surrey, Alathea Talbot, countess of, ?-1654 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    From: Iconography of Vandyke.Illustrissima et Excellentissima Domina; Dna; Alathea Talbot, etc. Comitissa Arundelliae & Surriae, etc. et prima Comitissa Angliae. Ant. van Dyck Eques pinxit W.Hollar fecit 1646 Antverpiae. [Jon. Meissens] excudit. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 26.7 x 19.7 cm. Singer No. 1129/3569. Dutuit No. l32.2e. Mauquoy H. No: 130.11.
  - 0055. Arundel and Surrey, Thomas Howard, earl of Norfolk, 1488-1554 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Tho.s Howardus Duxet Comes Norfolciae Comes Surriae, Dns Howard Moubray Bruse, Comes Marescallus Sum? Thesauriarius et Admiralius Angliae./Cum privilegis Reg. Hans Holbein pinxlt. Visitur in Aedibus Arondelianis Londini. Vorsterinan fecit. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. In right upper corner:"Ae. 66/Obyt 1554, (sic)." Engraving. 27.3 x 19.5 cm. Plate trimmed off.
  - 0056. Arundel and Surrey, Thomas Howard, earl of Norfolk, 1586-1646 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Statesman, English. Illustrissimus and Exellentissimus Dominus/Thomas Howardorum Primus Comes Ar/undeliae, et Surriae Primus Comes and Comes Marescallus Angliae. B.Moncornet excudit.
  - 0057. Arundel and Surrey, Thomas Howard, earl of Norfolk, 1586-1646 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Thomas Howard Earl of Arundel. Obit 1646. From an Original Picture R.Dunkarton sculpt. London published by S.Woodburn 1815. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 29.4 x 20.7 cm.
  - 0058. Arundel and Surrey, Thomas Howard, earl of Norfolk, ?-1572 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Thomas Howard Duke of Norfolk: beheaded A.D. 1572 from an original picture by Hams Holbein formely in the Collection of Lady Hyde. Now in the possession of Mr. R.Grave. London Published by Woodburn 1810. Bust in oblong looking left. Mezzotint. 15.8 x 10.8 cm.
  - 0059. Aston, Walter, 4th baron, 1660-1748 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Walter, First Lord of Aston. From the original in the Possession of Thomas Blount Esq.r. Drawn by R.W.Satchwell & Engraved (with Permission) by R.Cooper. London. Published Dec.r 1, 1815 by Lackington, Allen & Co. and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orine & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 36.9 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 0060. Astruc, Jean, 1684-1766 (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
    Astruc./C.Monnet mv. Grave par Louis Halbou 1771. Head in oval looking right in oblong. Engraving. 26.5 x 18.7 cm. Singer No. 1180/3687.
  - 0061. Atterbury, Francis, bp. of Rochester, 1662-1732 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
    Franciscus Atterbury,/gewesener Bischoff zu Rochester.IFritzsch sc:Hanb: Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 14.9 x 9.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 0062. Atticus, Herodes, 2nd century A.D. (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
    Herodes Atticus. P.Dujardin eng. Gebbie and Co. Unframed sculpture bust facing viewer. Photo-engraving. 36.5 x 26.7 cm. Torn from book.
  - 0063. Auersperg, Anton Alexander von [Anastasius Grün], 1806-1876 (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
    Auersperg (Anastasius Grün). Schertle. Nach Biow's Lichtbild. gedr. v. E. d. Gust. May in Frankfurt a MI Verlag u. Eigenthum der S.S.Schmerberschen Buchhandlung Nachfolger K.Heller in Frankfurt a M. Unframed bust looking left. Lithograph. 29.3 x 19.7 cm.
  - 0064. Augustus, Gajus Julius Caesar Octavianus, 2nd emperor of Rome, 63 B.C.-14 A.D. (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)